

Digital Product Designer

I'm a **UX** and **UI** designer with a background in ocean conservation. Years of research and consulting brought skills I now depend on through the **user-centered design process**—from competitive analysis to polished deliverables. Opportunities that excite me the most involve **distilling information** into **slick visuals** and **interactions**.

Recent Projects

Dively | Mobile mockups and animated interactions

Concept, brand, and prototype for a mobile app for scuba divers. View case study: kelseyjacobsen.design/dively

Dogear | Desktop and mobile prototype

Concept, brand, and prototype for a cloud storage platform to ease the writing process. View case study: kelseyjacobsen.design/dogear

Recent Work Experience

Freelance Designer

Multiple clients, September 2019-present

I am assisting several individuals and organizations with branding and digital product design. This includes creating:

- New logo, name, and website for a small business owner
- Look and feel for a collection of open source curriculum materials
- Data dashboard for a nonprofit displaying global energy use data

Director (formerly Associate, then Senior Associate)

Blue Earth Consultants, a Division of Eastern Research Group, 2014-2019

As a senior team member, I assisted coastal conservation/management clients in developing strong organizational strategies.

- Research: Led surveys, interviews, web research, and analysis
- Deliverables: Presented processes, strategic documents, and graphics
- Brand identity: Overhauled the Division's deliverable look and feel
- Project management: Managed clients, projects, and timelines

Education

Digital Product Design

Bloc. 2018-2019

Completed a 1,500+ hour project-based program under the mentorship of accomplished design professionals; led the full design process for two products plus front-end coding (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery).

Master of Environmental Science and Management

Bren School of Environmental Science & Management, 2010-2012

Bachelor of Arts, Environmental Studies (Minors in Art and French)

Connecticut College, 2004-2008

www.kelseyjacobsen.design linkedin.com/in/kelseyingrid Oakland, CA

Skills

- Survey design and problem identification
- Qualitative and quantitative analysis
- Mapping user stories and flows
- Wireframing and prototyping
- User and preference testing
- Branding and style guides
- Design system implementation
- Front-end coding

Tools

- Adobe Illustrator, InDesign, AfterEffects, LightRoom
- Atom
- Figma
- Google Forms
- Git/GitHub
- InVision
- Keynote, Pages, Numbers for Mac
- Microsoft PowerPoint, Word, Excel, Outlook
- Principle
- Sketch
- Tableau
- UsabilityHub
- Whimsical

Side Pursuits

- Trail running
- Scuba diving
- Loosely following new recipes
- Illustrating a book
- Leash training my cat